Brendan MacCabe

Data Solutions Specialist * CRM * CDP's * Strategist * Visualiser * Innovator

PROFILE:

 Looking to take next step as a data specialist delivering expertise and business solutions in the fields of CRM, campaign management, CDP's, data visualisation, consumer insight, targeting and customer segmentation. Leveraging 20+ years of data analyst and CRM manager experience to deliver quality, efficiency and real business impact.

CAREER PATH:

- In March 2024, departed role as CRM & Data Insight Manager for EDF and seeking next step in the field of data driven solutions for business.
- Career experience includes both extensive technical hands on delivery and senior team leadership for CRM and marketing functions.
- Most recent role with EDF responsible for a CRM team of 15 data professionals across UK and India, serving an extensive range of customer data solutions to meet objectives of retention, upsell, acquisition, account management and company obligations.

CONTACT

- 07967787517
- brendanmaccabe@gmail.com
- **Website**
- LinkedIn
- P Brighton, UK.

SKILLS & INTEREST

- CRM campaign solutions
- Campaign tools & CDPs
- Data Visualisation
- · Consumer Insight
- Targeting & Segmentation
- Customer contact strategy
- Database Management
- Al evolution
- A First Class Honours degree in IT & data field, and range of data analyst positions prior to 12 years in a senior manger leadership role, all concerned with precise, effective and high performing customer data solutions.
- Extensive experience of delivering quality data products across the marketing campaign life cycle, including communication deployment, consumer insight, data visualisation, campaign design, customer segmentations, audience targeting & performance reporting.
- In 2023/24, particular interest in campaign strategy, optimisation and efficiency, further developing data solutions with data science, machine learning and following closely the evolution of AI in business.

CAREER HISTORY

- EDF
 - Senior CRM & Data
 Insights Manager
 Oct 2021 March 2024
 - Senior CRM Manager
 Sep 2016 Sep 2021
 - Customer DataManagerJan 2010 Aug 2016
- Senior CRM team manager leading a virtual team of 15 data and insight analysts with 10 analysts in India + 5 at multiple UK locations.
- Provision of data driven campaign solutions, serving a wide range of business objectives within our Retail, Operational and Marketing teams.
- Solutions for c. 60 mil comms delivered in 2023, and responsible for c. 700 mil comms during EDF tenure as analyst + manager.
- Data selection, segmentation & deployment to customer and prospect audiences across email, DM, outbound, SMS & digital contact channels.
- Relationship owner with key suppliers including TCS India (offshore CRM team resources), CACI (data targeting products), HCL (campaign tooling).
- Data relationship owner for key business projects including campaign tool reviews, system / database migrations and acquisition of external datasets.
- Design and build of 30+ Tableau data visualisation solutions for effective campaign targeting, data insights and performance reporting enabling marketers quick access to information for campaign design and insights.
- Data Science model integrations for campaign targeting.
- Campaign consultant for effective targeting approaches, channel strategy and journey design for high performing campaigns.
- Lead for data quality, DPA, GDPR and compliance for CRM data solutions.
- Hands on design and build of campaign selections, customer segmentations and targeting models (eg. Cost of living crisis, Covid vulnerability models).

	 Self briefed insight deep dives - eg. campaign contact levels, customer vulnerability, smart meter lifestage - for knowledge share with marketing teams to optimise campaign targeting and performance. Demographic and behavioural data expertise with extensive knowledge and use of individual & address level UK datasets (60 mil & 27 mil records). JIRA project management and agile ways of working to manage challenging workloads that require continual and effective prioritisation.
RAPP UK Senior Data Analyst Sep 2009 – Dec 2009	 Digital marketing agency role responsible for design, build and deployment of daily / weekly email marketing campaigns with Alterian campaign. Clients include Post Office, Lovefilm & Cancer Research UK.
EDF Senior Data Analyst Jan 2004 - Aug 2009	 Campaign design, build and deployment for EDF marketing campaigns across channels of email, DM, outbound telesales. Marketing and service communications to 3 mil EDF customer base and data solutions for c. 20 mil comms per year. Oracle database, SQL / TOAD programming.
Thales Sensors Defence Oracle DBA Feb 2002 - Mar 2003	 Oracle database and MYSQL programming. Database design, build and maintain for company and customer datasets.

TOOLS / SKILLS		
Oracle, Redshift, Snowflake	Data stores for organisation, access and views of industry, customer & prospect datasets, scheduled jobs to ensure safe and secure daily refresh routines.	
Campaign Tools & CDP's - HCL UNICA, Exponea, Blueshift.	Campaign journey design, build, test and deployment for multi channel customer communications and contact history stores with HCL UNICA. 2 years experience utilising Exponea and CDP tool reviews assessing Blueshift, Braze, AWS.	
SQL	20+ years experience of SQL programming for querying, creating, developing databases for campaign, insight & visualisation solutions.	
TOAD / Snowflake Web UI	Interface for efficient access, interrogation and views of customer datasets.	
Tableau	Hands on design, build & share of Tableau visualisations for effective data driven decision making to a marketing team user community of 100+ users.	
Matillion	Data transformations for effective data presentation and integrity, to enable effective campaign platform for UNICA solutions.	
Miro – Virtual Whiteboard	Effective share and presentation of information across team and stakeholders to assist team management, knowledge share and project coordination.	
JIRA	Task management for efficient control & delivery of individual / team workload and stakeholder management.	

EDUCATION	
First class degree - BSc Business Computing	Leeds Beckett University 1997 - 2001.
3 A-levels	Cardinal Newman High School - Sept 1990 - Jul 97.
9 GCSEs.	Cardinal Newman Sec. School - Sept 1997 - Jul 99.